(忆往昔)
我们会找到撂倒路西法的办法
We're gonna find a way to beat the devil, okay?
不如你们引诱路西法到牢笼边  而我跳进去
What if you guys lead the devil to the edge and I jump in?
同意
Yes.
萨姆早不在了
Sammy's long gone.
你现在有什么打算呢
What you are gonna do now?
回天堂吧  我想
Return to heaven, I suppose.
天堂
Heaven?
鉴于米迦勒也被关进了牢笼
With Michael in the cage,
想必此刻上面必定是一片混乱
I'm sure it's total anarchy up there.
所以呢  现在你是老大了吗
So, what, you're the new sheriff in town?
上面正在进行内战
It's Civil War up there!
如果能打败拉斐尔  我们就可以结束这一切
If we can beat Raphael, we can end this!
一旦油燃烧起来
When the oil burns,
没有天使敢触碰或是跨过那火焰
no angel can touch or pass through the flames,
除非是活得不耐烦了
or he dies.
他的灵魂  不见了
It's his soul. It's gone.
当我们这些怪物死掉时  我们该魂归何处呢
When we freaks die, where do we go?
我们不上天堂  也不入地狱
Not heaven, not hell.
-炼狱  -而我想得到它
- Purgatory. - And I want it.
人类的灵魂远比你想象的珍贵得多
The human soul is more valuable than you can imagine.
是为了那些灵魂吧
This is about the souls.
巴尔萨泽为了增加你们的战斗力
That angel went and created
改变历史来徒增了五万灵魂
50,000 new souls for your war machine.
夏娃  万物之母
Eve, the mother of all of us.
-我只想要克劳力的命  -那么恐怕你来晚了
- It's Crowley I want dead. - Well, you're too late there.
那小英国佬早在数月前被燃烧殆尽了
That little limey mook roasted months ago.
克劳力还活着
Crowley's alive.
老实说  小卡
Really, Cass...
事情变得越来越荒唐了
This is getting ridiculous.
你还想要我帮你擦几次屁股
How many times am I gonna have to clean up your messes?
(如今)
说起来  我已经
You know, I've...
已经生存了很长时间
I've been here for a very long time.
过去的林林总总都还历历在目
And I remember many things.
我还记得在一个海岸边
I remember being at a shoreline,
发现一只正在努力往岸上扑腾的小灰鱼
watching a little gray fish heave itself up on the beach
一个年长的兄弟对我说
And an older brother saying,
别踩到那条鱼  卡西迪奥
"Don't step on that fish, Castiel.
那条鱼还大有用处呢
Big plans for that fish."
我还记得巴别塔  37英尺高
I remember the tower of Babel... all 37 feet of it,
在当时来说  算是惊骇世俗
which I suppose was impressive at the time.
当它倒塌时  他们叫喊着神降天谴
And when it fell, they howled divine wrath.
拜托
But come on.
干粪筑的墙壁也就只能堆那么高了
Dried dung can only be stacked so high.
我还记得该隐和亚伯
I remember Cain and Abel...
大卫和歌利亚
David and Goliath...
所多玛和蛾摩拉
Sodom and Gomorrah.
当然了
And, of course,
我记得最非凡的那件事
I remember the most remarkable event --
之所以非比寻常是因为从未发生
Remarkable because it never came to pass.
阻止天启降世的是两个小哥
It was averted by two boys...
和一个老酒鬼
An old drunk...
还有一个堕落天使
And a fallen angel.
荡气回肠的故事
The grand story.
我们颠覆了结局
And we ripped up the ending
抛开了一切规则
And the rules...
以及命运
And destiny...
仅将自由和选择权紧握于手
Leaving nothing but freedom and choice.
这一切都尽如人意  除了...
Which is all well and good, except...
如果我做的选择是错误的呢
...Well, what if I've made the wrong choice?
我该如何自知呢
How am I supposed to know?
我有些本末倒置了
I'm getting ahead of myself.
让我来讲述我的故事
Let me tell you my story.
告诉你这一切的原委
Let me tell you everything.
[邪恶力量 第6季第20集]
好啊  迪恩
Hello, Dean.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
当然  我
Yeah, I'm...
好得很  你呢
I'm fine. How are you?
只是想来打个招呼
Just wanted to check in.
关于小恶魔的死活  有什么消息吗
So, any word on, uh, Satan jr. being alive?
我  还在查  相信我
I'm...Looking, believe me.
我只是想不通  克劳力是怎么骗到我的
I just don't understand how Crowley could've tricked me.
因为他是个诡计多端的混球
Well, he's a tricky son of a bitch, that's how.
无所谓了
Doesn't matter.
但如果他真的活着
But if he is up and kicking,
重要的要找到他
then what does matter is finding him,
拧掉他的脑袋  爆他的菊
ripping his head off, and shoving it up his ass.
你们呢  有什么收获没
What about you? Have you found anything?
没有  还没任何发现
No, nothing yet.
萨姆人呢
Where's Sam?
忙乎着呢
He's keeping busy.
这会儿他正在奥马哈追踪一个灯灵
He's tracking a djinn in Omaha as we speak.
事实上  我正要去跟他汇合
In fact, I'm heading out there right now to meet up with him.
可以的话我会跟你去
Well, I'd come if I could.
我明白  没事儿
Yeah, no, I-I get it. No worries.
但你会来找我们的  对吧小卡
But, Cass, you'll call, right?
如果你遇上什么大麻烦的话
If you get into real trouble?
你好  伙计
Howdy, partner.
你有何收获
What have you found?
收获颇丰
I've found a lot of things.
比如说...
For example...
夏娃的大脑已经彻底死亡
Eve's brain? Dead as a tinned kipper.
但是...
Yet...
...出于某种原因...
...for some reason...
她仍在一直产卵
She keeps laying eggs.
注意看
Watch this.
这小吸血鬼能感应到每一次触碰
Chocula here feels every tickle.
这有什么好处
What is that good for?
除了让人感到性奋之外  我就不知道了
Apart from the obvious erotic value, you got me.
你说过夏娃能够开启炼狱之门
You said Eve could open the door to purgatory.
没错  我的确说过
Correct. I did.
而且我相信  如果她还活着的话
And I'm confident that she could have
可能已经把门打开了
if she was still alive!
她是帮我们达成目的的最佳人选
Single best chance to get over the rainbow,
结果温氏兄弟却把她给杀了
and the Winchesters killed her!
当时局势不受控制
It was unavoidable.
是你太不给力了  小卡
You screwed up, Cass.
是你任由猎狗咬死了野鸡
You let the hounds mangle the pheasant,
到头来还要我去收拾烂摊子
and now I am up to my elbows in it.
你到底想说什么
What is your point?
我想说的是...
The point is...
你分心了  这让我很担忧
you're distracted, and that makes me nervous.
我在履行我的职责
I am holding up my end.
可不是嘛
Ah, yes.
不过你还办了点别的事吧
But is that all you're holding?
瞧...
See...
你的外套上沾满了
The stench of that impala's
那辆黑斑羚的恶臭  天使大人
all over your overcoat, angel.
我们不是说好了吗
I thought we'd agreed --
再也不去找他们兄弟俩
No more nights out with the boys.
我不过是跟迪恩聊了几句
I spoke with Dean.
我要随时掌握他们手上的信息
I needed to know what they know.
哪方面的
About what?
关于我的事情吗
About me, maybe?
因为我有足够的理由相信
'cause I happen to have it on good authority
你那两只小宠物
that your two little pets
最近正卯足了劲想抓我呢
are currently trying to hunt me down!
原谅我的直白
Forgive me.
但我认为你在此事上大概有点利益冲突
But I think you might have a little conflict of interest here.
克劳力所言极是
Crowley had a point, of course.
我的利益的确发生了冲突
My interest was conflicted.
我仍然把自己当做温氏兄弟的守护者
I still considered myself the Winchesters' guardian.
毕竟
After all...
是他们教会了我如何抵抗...
they taught me how to stand up...
喂  混球
Hey! Ass butt!
...为何而奋斗...
...what to stand for...
以及在抵抗和奋斗过后通常会发生什么
and what generally happens to you when you do.
我当时死了
I was done.
生命终结了
I was over.
但后来最不可思议的事情发生了
And then the most extraordinary thing happened.
我竟然复活了
I was put back.
并且我们取得了胜利
And we had won.
阻止了世界末日
We stopped armageddon.
但却代价惨重
But at a terrible cost.
于是我知道了自己接下来的使命
And so I knew what I had to do next.
我再度前往地狱
Once again, I went to harrow hell,
将萨姆从路西法的牢笼中解救了出来
to free Sam from Lucifer's cage.
那是个几乎不可能完成的任务
It was nearly impossible,
但我心中充满了自信与使命感
but I was so full of confidence, of mission.
而现在看来  那只是自负...
I see now that was arrogance...
和傲慢罢了...
hubris...
因为我并没有真正地将萨姆复活
Because, of course, I hadn't truly raised Sam --
不是完整的他
Not all of him.
有时我们很幸运  能够得到告诫
Sometimes we're lucky enough to be given a warning.
而这本应是给我的告诫
This should have been mine.
拜托了
Please.
我求你了  卡西迪奥
I'm begging you, Castiel.
杀了温氏兄弟吧
Just kill the Winchesters.
-不行  -好吧
- No. - Fine.
那我只能亲自动手了
Then I'll do it myself.
即使你杀了他们  我也会把他们救回来
If you kill them, I'll just bring them back again.
不  你不能
No, you won't.
那地方连你都无能为力  相信我
Not where I'll put 'em. Trust me.
我说了  不行
I said...no.
不必担心他们
Don't worry about them.
不必担心...
Don't worry about --
难道路西法不担心吗
What, like Lucifer didn't worry?
米迦勒呢
Or Michael?
莉莉丝  阿拉斯泰尔和阿撒兹勒不担心吗
Or Lilith or Alistair or Azazel didn't worry?!
难道在这场战局里只有我一个人
Am I the only game piece on the board
没低估那两个穿牛仔裤的温家双煞吗
who doesn't underestimate those denim-wrapped nightmares?!
你专心找炼狱吧
Just find purgatory.
如果你找不到  我们俩都得死
If you don't, we will both die
不停地经历死亡  直到时间的尽头
again and again, until the end of time.
温家兄弟找不到你的
The Winchesters won't get to you.
让他们来找我吧
Let them get to me!
我会把他们的心挖出来
I'll tear their friggin' hearts out!
我得说  瑞德
I got to tell you, Redd...
对于一个猥琐的
for a filthy,
低贱至极的再生侠来说
lower-than-snake-spit hellspawn,
你倒是成了一个像模像样的猎魔人
You seem to have turned yourself into a damn fine hunter.
我真不知道是要杀了你还是亲亲你
I don't know whether to kill you or kiss you.
求你杀了我吧
Oh, please, kill me.
是你摧毁了在天鹅谷的
That was you that dug out that nest of vamps
吸血鬼巢穴  是吗
back in Swan Valley, wasn't it?
干得漂亮
That was nice work.
一次搞定八个  捆绑结实
Eight of 'em in one go, roped and tied.
然后你送他们到克劳力那  对吗
And then you brought them to Crowley, right?
你凹凸了  乡巴佬
Read the papers, redneck.
国王已经死了
The king is dead.
克劳力还活着
Crowley's alive.
你的举动就证明了这一点
You prove it just by being,
你这个可怜又愚蠢的混蛋
you poor, dumb jackass.
克劳力还活着  他的势力仍遍布天下
Crowley's alive. His nets are still out.
只是现在他是用你们这些笨蛋
Except now he's using you schmucks
来替他抓捕怪物
to hunt his monsters.
去你的
Up yours.
瑞德
Redd...
克劳力在哪
Where's Crowley?
什么都不说吗
No? Nothing?
那好吧
Oh, okay, then.
那么享受一下这个吧
Here, hang on to this for a bit.
那你都给他说什么了
So, what'd you tell him?
没什么  放松点
Nothing. Just relax.
什么情况
What's the hubbub?
我见到小卡了
I saw Cass.
两小时前他飞进我的车
He popped in on me about two hours back.
你给他说什么了
What'd you tell him?
什么都没说
Nothing, all right?
我告诉他我们在追捕一些怪物
Told him we were on some crap monster hunt.
他不知道我们在接近克劳力
He doesn't know that we're getting close to Crowley.
他是我们的朋友
You know, he's our friend...
现在我们竟然对他信口雌黄
and we are lying to him through our teeth.
-迪恩  -他就是烧错骨头了
- Dean-- - So he burned the wrong bones.
也就是克劳力耍了他
So Crowley tricked him.
他是一个天使
He's an angel.
他简直就一个小天真
He is the Balki Bartokomous of heaven!
他有可能出错
He can make a mistake!
现在谁都没说什么
Nobody's saying nothing yet.
你认为小卡和克劳力是一伙的
You think that Cass is in with Crowley.
克劳力
Crowley?
听着  我只是说我不知道
Look, I'm just saying I don't know.
我都恨自己有这样的想法
Now, look, I hate myself for even thinking it,
但是我不知道
but I don't know.
迪恩  他也是我们的朋友
Look, Dean, he's our friend, too, okay?
我会为他而死  真的  但是
And I'd die for him. I would, but...
我希望咱们是错的
Look, I'm praying we're wrong here.
但是如果我们没错
But if we ain't...
如果哪怕有一点点可能
If there's a snowball of a snowball's chance here...
那就意味着我们得对抗一个黑化的超人
that means we're dealing with a superman who's gone dark side...
也就是说我们得小心谨慎
which means we've got to be cautious,
得心思敏捷
we got to be smart,
也许还得储存些氪石(超人的克星)
and maybe stock up on some kryptonite.
所以你就是超人的"女人"了
This makes you Lois Lane.
一次解决一个问题
Look, one problem at a time here.
我们得在那个混蛋克劳力打开
We got to find Crowley now,
那见鬼的炼狱前找到他
before the damn fool cracks open purgatory.
他们已经开始怀疑了
So they already suspected.
-克劳力在哪  -去你的
- Where's Crowley? - Up yours.
最糟糕的部分就是迪恩
And the worst part was Dean.
他非常努力地想相信我
He was trying so hard to be loyal,
但他的直觉告诉他并非如此
but every instinct telling him otherwise.
我不知道克劳力在哪
I don't know where Crowley is!
你确定吗
Are you sure about that?
我们可有的是时间折磨你
Because we can twist again all the way to next summer.
天啊
Oh, god!
我从没见过他
I never even met him!
我不和克劳力直接打交道
I don't deal with Crowley direct.
那你和谁打交道
Well, who do you deal with?
调度员
The dispatcher.
一个叫埃尔斯沃思的恶魔
A demon named Ellsworth.
如果有个恶魔和鲍比做的工作一样的话
If there was a demon counterpart to Bobby Singer,
非埃尔斯沃思莫属
Ellsworth would be it.
不  听我说
No, listen to me.
不  我不关心
No. I don't care.
我要你去新墨西哥州
I want you to get down to New Mexico
然后把那个雪怪抓过来
and bag me that wendigo!
等会
Hell. Hang on.
什么
What?
因为老大说我们用不着他们了
Because the boss says we're done with them.
联邦调查局  我是托马斯
FBI. Thomas speaking.
是的  是我派去的  谢谢来电确认
Absolutely, I sent them. Thank you for calling to check.
祝你过的愉快
Have a nice day, now.
再见
Bye-bye.
嘿  嘿  不
Hey, hey, hey! No!
不要放在这里  你们个二货
Not in here, you friggin' yeti.
放后面去
Out back!
这些恶魔会带领温家兄弟找到克劳力
These demons would lead the Winchesters to Crowley,
克劳力会把他俩杀死
and Crowley would tear their hearts out.
我靠
Oh, hell.
我别无选择
I had no choice.
我是为了保护温家兄弟
I did it to protect the boys.
或是保护我自己
Or to protect myself.
我自己都糊涂了
I-I don't know anymore.
后面啥也没有
Hey. Clear from the back.
恶魔得到线报然后撤退了吗
Demons get tipped and bugged out?
也许他们在躲我们
Maybe they run from us now.
想法不错  对吧
I mean, that would be a nice thought, right?
如果是真的就好了
Yeah, if that's what happened.
隐藏
Hiding...
欺骗
Lying...
毁灭证据
Sweeping away evidence.
我的动机曾经很单纯
And my motives used to be so pure.
"救"了萨姆之后
After supposedly "saving" Sam,
我终于回到了天堂
I finally returned to heaven.
当然了  天堂不止一个
Of course, there isn't one heaven.
每个灵魂都有自己的天堂
Each soul generates its own paradise.
我喜欢那个1953年溺死在浴缸中的
I favored the eternal Tuesday afternoon
那个孤僻的男人创造的永恒的星期二下午
of an autistic man who drowned in a bathtub in 1953.
你还活着
You're alive.
是的
Yes.
卡西迪奥  我们亲眼看见路西法杀了你
Castiel, we saw Lucifer destroy you.
但是我回来了
Well, I came back.
那路西法和米迦勒呢
But Lucifer? Michael?
他们不在了
They're gone.
是上帝  对吧
It was God, wasn't it?
不是
No.
是温家兄弟
It was the Winchesters.
他们阻止了天启
They brought down the apocalypse.
但是你打败了大天使  卡西迪奥
But you beat the Archangels, Castiel.
上帝把你救了回来
God brought you back.
卡西  他选择了你
He chose you, Cass...
来领导我们
to lead us.
不
No.
现在没人领导我们了
No one leads us anymore.
我们可以自己做决定
We're all free to make our own choices
选择我们自己的命运
and to choose our own fates.
上帝意在何为
What does god want?
上帝想让你们自由
God wants you to have freedom.
我们用自由来做什么
But what does he want us to do with it?
如果我那时知道现在明白的一切
If I knew then what I know now...
我可能会说
I might have said...
很简单
"It's simple.
自由是一截绳子
"Freedom is a length of rope.
上帝想让你们用自由之绳上吊
God wants you to hang yourself with it."
回到天堂的头几周
Those first weeks back in heaven
日子异常地艰辛
were surprisingly difficult.
向天使们解释自由之说
Explaining freedom to angels
简直是对牛弹琴
is a bit like teaching poetry to fish.
然后拉斐尔出现了
And then there was Raphael...
你来了
You came.
我很欣赏你的勇气
I appreciate the courage that takes.
这个天堂是谁的
Whose heaven is this?
肯莱的(安然公司创始人)  我借来用用
Ken Lay's. I'm borrowing it.
我还是怀疑他是否够资格进入天堂
I still question his admittance here.
他很虔诚
He's devout.
压倒了一切
Trumps everything.
你要干什么
What do you want?
明天
Tomorrow --
我号召了众天使集结
I've called for a full assembly of the holy host.
你要在我面前跪下
You'll kneel before me
然后宣誓效忠  明白了吗
and pledge allegiance to the flag, all right?
效忠谁
And what flag is that?
是我  卡西迪奥
Me, Castiel.
宣誓效忠于我
Allegiance to me.
你开玩笑的吧
Are you joking?
我看起来像开玩笑吗
Do I look like I'm joking?
你从来都一副面瘫脸
You never look like you're joking.
你背叛了上帝  天堂和我
You rebelled -- against God, heaven, and me.
现在你要赎罪
Now you will atone.
我们先把路西法和米迦勒从牢笼里释放
We'll start by freeing Lucifer and Michael from their cage.
然后我们再继续上演好戏
And then we'll get our show back on the road.
拉斐尔  不要
Raphael...No.
没有必要费尽心思开启天启
The apocalypse doesn't have to be fought!
当然必要  那是上帝的旨意
Of course it does. It's god's will.
你怎么能这么说
How can you say that?!
因为这就是我想要的
Because it's what I want.
其他的天使不会任你恣意妄为
Well, the other angels won't let you.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
你心里最清楚不过了  卡西迪奥
You know better than anyone, Castiel.
他们是战士
They're soldiers.
他们生来就要听命  不是为自由而造
They weren't built for freedom. They were built to follow.
那我便会出面阻止你
Then I won't let you.
真的吗
Really?
就凭你吗
You?
谈及我的兄长
I'm not ashamed to say
将我修理的很惨  我不觉羞愧
that my big brother knocked me into next week.
明天你会向我臣服  卡西迪奥
Tomorrow you kneel, Castiel...
不然你及你的随从都得死
or you and anyone with you dies.
这地方很干净
The place is clean.
是没错  但是
Yeah, but it's...
未免也太干净了点
It's like "Mr. Clean" clean, you know?
跟普通恶魔相比  这简直就算强迫症了
It's kind of OCD for your average demon.
嗯  那现在呢
Yeah. So what now?
召唤小卡
We'd call Cass.
什么
What?
通常我们都会在这种时候叫小卡来帮忙
This is usually the point where we would call Cass for help.
我们已经谈过这事了
We talked about this.
没错  迪恩
Yeah, Dean.
不  都是你们在说  我只是在听
No, you talked. I listened.
那可是小卡啊  两位
This is Cass, guys.
我说  当我们孤立无援
I mean, when there was no one...
无法逃脱  真的陷入困境
and we were stuck -- and I mean really stuck --
是他挺身而出
he broke ranks.
他为我们两肋插刀上刀山下火海
He has gone to the mat cut and bleeding for us
不知道有他妈多少回了
so many freakin' times.
这是小卡啊
This is Cass!
在没证据之前  我们至少应该相信他的清白
Don't we owe him the benefit of the doubt at least?
卡西迪奥
Castiel...
这事很重要
This is really important, okay?
我们得跟你谈谈
Um... We really need to talk to you.
卡西迪奥
Castiel...
赶紧出现吧
Come on in.
但我没有现身
But I didn't go to them...
因为我知道他们拥有我无法作答的疑问
Because I knew they would have questions I couldn't answer...
因为我害怕了
Because I was afraid.
小卡很忙
Cass is busy.
没事  我们也很忙
That's all right. We are, too.
走吧
Come on.
又回到起点了
Back to square one.
好啊  我们现在怎么做
Great. Well, what do we do now?
既然我们抓到过一个恶魔猎人
Well, we caught one hunter demon before.
-还能再抓到的  -迪恩
- We can do it again. - Dean!
克劳力向你问好
Crowley says "Hi".
克劳力派出了他的得力干将
Crowley sent his very best.
我也跟那三人一样惊讶万分
I was caught as much by surprise as the rest of them.
然而我尚有其它选择
And it left me with yet another choice.
我可以现身处理那些恶魔
I could reveal myself and smite the demons.
当然  那一定不讨克劳力的喜欢
Of course, Crowley wouldn't like it.
可话又说回来  他们是我的朋友
But on the other hand, they were my friends.
一刹那间
For a brief moment...
我又做回了我自己
I was me again.
见到你真好  小卡
It is good to see you, Cass.
你还好吧
You all right?
没事
Yeah.
还真及时啊  小卡
Perfect timing, Cass.
很高兴我找到你们了
I'm glad I found you.
我有消息告诉你们
I come with news.
是吗  说来听听
Yeah? What?
我确信克劳力还活着
I firmly believe Crowley is alive.
是啊  还用你说吗  酷杰克(出自《神探酷杰克》)
Yeah. You think, Kojak?
鲍比  关于小卡再次救了我们的小命
Well, Bobby, what do we think about Cass saving our asses...
该作何感想呢
again?
我们该给你道个歉
I think we owe you an apology.
为什么
Why?
这段时间我们都在追捕克劳力
We've been hunting Crowley this whole time...
瞒着不让你知道
and keeping it from you.
我们之前以为
We thought...
你在跟他合作
you were working with him.
你们以为什么
You thought what?
我知道  疯了  是吧
I know. It's crazy, right?
只是你烧错了尸骨
It's just that you torched the wrong bones.
那不重要  我们  错了
It doesn't matter. We -- we were wrong.
你们
You know...
本可直问无妨
you could've just asked me.
我们是应该那么做
And we should have.
我们不应该对你有所怀疑  那是
We never should've doubted you. It's...
希望你能原谅我们
I just hope you can forgive us.
还真是奇事不断
Wonders never cease.
他们再度信任我了
They trusted me again.
但这只是另一个谎言
But it was just another lie.
没关系
It's forgotten.
谢了
Thanks.
是啊
Yeah.
谢了  小卡
Thanks, Cass.
不过是有点荒谬
It is a little absurd, though.
我知道  我知道
I know, I know.
黑化版的超人
Superman going to the dark side.
我还是卡西迪奥啊
I'm still just Castiel.
我们可以把氪星石扔一边了  是不是
I guess we can put away the kryptonite, right?
没错
Exactly.
当然了  我当时没有意识到
Of course, I didn't realize it at the time.
但是一切都结束了
But it was all over.
就在那一刻  就那样结束了
Right then, just like that.
你竟派恶魔去杀他们
You sent demons after them?
你杀了我的猎人  我怎么就不能杀你的
You kill my hunters. Why can't I kill yours?
他们是我的朋友
They're my friends.
你不能拥有朋友  再也不能了
You can't have friends, not anymore.
我的天啊  你要失控了
I mean, my God. You're losing it!
我很好
I'm fine.
是啊
Yeah.
你可是心理健康的代言人呢
You're the very picture of mental health.
拜托  你以为我不知道这都为了什么吗
Come on. You don't think I know what this is all about?
说来听听
Enlighten me.
弥天大谎  温氏兄弟还相信你
The big lie,  the Winchesters still buy it.
相信你是好小卡  正直的小卡
The good Cass, the righteous Cass.
只要他们还相信
And long as they still believe it,
你就也相信
you get to believe it.
不过我得告诉你  小乖乖
Well, I got news for you, kitten.
当了婊子就别想人家给你立牌坊
A whore is a whore is a whore.
这话我只说一次
I'm only gonna say this once.
你敢动他们一根毫毛
If you touch a hair on their heads,
我就毁掉一切
I will tear it all down.
我们的约定  所有一切
Our arrangement, everything.
我还是个天使呢  我会灭了你
I'm still an angel, and I will bury you.
我扪心自问
I asked myself,
"我跟这种下三滥在一起干嘛"
"What was I doing with this vermin?"
这叫哪门子合作啊
This is not how synergy works!
可我很清楚是为什么
As if I didn't already know the answer.
拉斐尔比我强壮
Raphael was stronger than me.
硬碰硬我是赢不了的
I wouldn't survive a straight fight.
所以我去找老朋友帮忙
So I went to an old friend for help.
可是当我看着他  却停了下来
But watching him, I stopped.
他牺牲了那么多
Everything he sacrificed,
我却还要向他要求更多
and I was about to ask him for more.
卡西迪奥
Ah, Castiel.
星期四天使
Angel of Thursday.
可惜今天不归你管  是不是
Just not your day is it?
你在这干嘛
What are you doing here?
我是为了帮我们俩一个忙
I want to help you help me help ourselves.
别拐弯抹角
Speak plain.
我想来谈一笔简单的交易  没别的
I want to discuss a simple business transaction. That's all.
你想做交易
You want to make a deal?
跟我吗
With me?
我是个天使  你个二货
I'm an angel, you ass.
我没有灵魂能卖给你
I don't have a soul to sell.
但那就是问题的关键  不是吗
But that's it, isn't it?
是全部的关键  灵魂
It's all of it. It's the souls.
说到底就是灵魂  不是吗
It all comes down to the souls in the end, doesn't it?
你到底在说些什么
What in the hell are you talking about?
我在说如何灭掉拉斐尔
I'm talking about Raphael's head on a pike.
我在说我们所有人的欢乐大结局
I'm talking about happy endings for all of us,
各方面的欢乐大结局
with all possible entendres intended.
来嘛
Come on.
就聊聊
Just a chat.
我没有兴趣跟你谈
I have no interest in talking with you.
干嘛不呢  人家很风趣滴
Why not? I'm very interesting.
来嘛  听我说完的
Come on. Hear me out.
就五分钟  免费的哟
Five minutes. No obligations.
我保证  不会浪费你的时间
I promise, I'll make it worth your while.
我不是傻子
I was no fool.
我知道克劳力是什么人物  他做过什么
I knew who Crowley was and what he did.
但是我比他聪明  比他强大
But I was smarter than him, stronger.
我现在知道我是太自大了
I see now that I was prideful.
而且很有可能  我就是个傻子
And in all likelihood, I was a fool.
这是哪里
Where are we?
认不出了  是不是
You don't recognize it, do you?
这是冥府  新升级版的
It's hades, new and improved.
我自己做的呢
I did it myself.
这是地狱吗
This is hell?
是啊  你看  老地方的毛病
Yeah. See, problem with the old place
是大部分的犯人就是受虐狂
was most of the inmates were masochists already.
总是有人说  谢谢您
A lot of "Thank you, sir.
再多来根红热的棍子捅捅我吧
Can I have another hot spike up the jacksie?"
但你看看他们
But just look at them.
没人喜欢排队
No one likes waiting in line.
他们排到了会怎样
And what happens when they reach the front?
什么都没有
Nothing.
再次回到队尾
They go right back to the end again.
效率很高吧
That's efficiency.
你还剩四分钟
You have four minutes left.
你打算怎么对付拉斐尔
What are you planning to do about Raphael?
除了屈服或者死  我还能做什么
What can I do besides submit or die?
屈服或死  你以为你是法国人吗
Submit or die? What are you, French?
为什么不对着干
How about resist?
你也知道  我没他强
I'm not strong enough, and you know it.
你一个人是不够强
Ah, not on your own, you're not.
但你不是一个人啊  对吧
But you're not on your own, are you?
有许多天使欣赏你
There's a lot of angels swooning over you.
"上帝的宠儿"
"God's favorite."
兄弟  你在他们眼中可是很有魅力
Buddy boy, you've got what they call sex appeal.
谢谢  有话直说吧
Thank you. Get to the point.
天使们需要领袖  这个人就是你
Angels need leaders, so be one.
集合你的人马
Gather your army
铲除所有巴结拉斐尔的天使
and kick the candy out of each and every angel that shows up for Raphael.
你是想说服我在天堂发起内战么
Are you proposing that I start a civil war in heaven?
答对了哟  告诉他奖品是什么
Ding! Ding! Ding! Tell him what he's won, Vanna.
你是想让我成为下一个路西法
You're asking me to be the next Lucifer.
别这样说
Please.
路西法缺乏父爱而且有暴力倾向
Lucifer was a petulant child with daddy issues.
小卡  你爱上帝  上帝也爱你
Cass, you love god. God loves you.
是他将你复活
He brought you back.
你不觉得他这么做
Did it occur to you that maybe he did this
是想让你成为新的领袖么
so you could be the new sheriff upstairs?
太荒谬了
This is ridiculous.
发动战争所需的力量
I mean, the amount of power that it would take
太过强大
to mount a war...
需要史无前例强大的力量  我知道
More than either of us have ever seen, yeah.
可是如果我说我知道如何拥有最强力量呢
But what if I said I knew how to go nuclear?
你什么意思
What do you mean?
炼狱呀  我可爱的小翅膀
Purgatory, my fine feathered friend.
炼狱
Purgatory.
试想一下
Just think about it.
一个未开发过的油井
An untapped oil well of
里面全是张牙舞爪的灵魂
every fanged, clawed soul.
你想  这些年来有多少了
I mean, what's that over the years?
三千万还是四千万呢
30 million? 40 million?
就在那  饱满丰富  供人拿取
Just sitting there, plump and rich for the taking.
既然以前没人找到  你怎么就能找到
How would you even find it when no one ever has?
我们需要专业的帮助
We'll need expert help.
谁
From whom?
当然是专家啊
From experts, of course.
我知道有两个奇奇怪怪的年轻人十分合适
I know of two eerily suited teen beat models
而且有大把时间
with time on their hands.
不行  迪恩不行
No. Not Dean.
他已经退出了  不能把他扯进来
He's retired, and he's to stay that way.
好吧
Fine.
那还有个秃顶的老家长
Then I know of a certain big, bald patriarch
可以做候补人选
I can take off the bench.
关键是
The point is...
他们能帮我们找到那些怪物
They can get us to the monsters.
那些怪物可以带我们找到炼狱
The monsters can get us to purgatory.
我很清楚
I know it.
这么做的话  你的代价是什么
And what's your price in all of this?
-仅仅一半  -一半
- Just half. - Half?
我的地位没那么稳定了
My position isn't all that stable, ducky.
那些灵魂能帮我
Those souls would help,
同样也能帮你
Just like they'd help you.
另外  难道你不想让我掌管地狱吗
Besides, wouldn't you rather have me in charge down here?
路西法可没这么好伺候
The devil you know...
这样没有意义
This is pointless.
你的计划时间太长  我现在就需要帮助
Your plan would take months, and I need help now.
既然这样
Granted.
的确
Yes.
但是为了向你展现我对此次计划的决心
But just to show you how serious I am about this scheme...
我先借你一些怎么样
How about I float you a little loan?
比如50大群
Say, 50 large?
来自地狱的五万只灵魂
50,000 souls from the pit.
你可以带他们去天堂
You can take them up to heaven.
示威一下
Make quite a showing.
要么这么干
It's either this
要么就是再来一次天启
or the apocalypse all over again.
你所奋斗的一切
Everything you've worked for --
以及萨姆和迪恩所努力的一切
everything that Sam and Dean has worked for
都化为乌有
gone.
卡西迪奥  你可以拯救我们
You can save us, Castiel.
上帝选择你来救我们
God chose you to save us.
而且我认为  在你内心深处
And I think...Deep down...
你懂的
You know that.
我真希望
I wish I could say
当时的傲慢没有战胜自己的理智...
I was clean of pride at that moment...
或者是之后
...or the next.
不会再有天启了
There will be no apocalypse.
把这话传出去
And let it be known...
跟随拉斐尔  便是与我为敌
You're either with Raphael or you're with me.
于是善意的初衷引导我走上了这条路
And so went the long road of good intentions...
一直走到今天的境地
The road that brought me here.
卡西迪奥
Castiel, uh...
我们需要借助一些你的力量
We need you for a little powwow down here,
快下来吧
so come on down.
随叫随到呀
Oh, Johnny on the spot.
你们还没离开
You're still here.
是啊  我们得把尸体埋掉
Yeah, we had to bury the bodies.
还发现了一些威士忌
And we found a little whiskey.
谢谢你能来
Thanks for coming.
要帮什么忙
How can I help?
这样...  我们想了个新方案
Oh, look. We, um... we have a new plan.
我们认为这办法能够找到克劳力
We think we've finally figured out a way to track down Crowley.
-什么办法  -就是你
- What is it? - It's you.
你们这是做什么
What are you doing?
我们得谈谈
We got to talk.
谈什么  放我出去
About what? Let me go!
谈谈超人
About superman.
还有氪晶体
And kryptonite.
你怎么会知道我说了这话
How'd you know what I said?
你监视我们多久了
How long you been watching us?
小卡  你知不知道什么人才搞监视
You know who spies on people, Cass?
-间谍  -等一等
- Spies. - Okay, just wait.
我都不知道你们在说什么
I don't even know what you mean.
这个恶魔巢穴怎么解释
What about this demon craphole?
这里怎么会
How is it so, uh...
干净得跟圣所一样
"Next to godliness" Clean in here?
克劳力又是怎么用假尸骨骗过你的
And how exactly did Crowley trick you with the wrong bones?
这事很难懂
It's hard to understand.
不太好解释
It's hard to explain.
放我出去  我出去之后再...
Just let me go. Let me out and I can...
你得看着我说话啊
You got to look at me, man.
你必须跟我坦白  告诉我这是怎么一回事
You got to level with me and tell me what's going on.
看着我的眼睛
Look me in the eye
告诉我你没跟克劳力同流合污
and tell me you're not working with Crowley.
你个兔崽子
You son of a bitch.
听我解释
Let me explain.
你跟他是一伙的
You're in it with him?
你和克劳力合伙试图找到炼狱
You and Crowley have been going after purgatory together?
早就是了对么  一直都是
You have, huh? This whole time.
我这么做是为了保护你  保护你们所有人
I did it to protect you. I did it to protect all of you.
怎么保护我们
Protect us how?
打开通往怪物乐园的通道吗
By opening a hole into monsterland!
小卡  他说的对
He's right, Cass.
只一瞬间  就放出了夏娃
One drop got through, and it was Eve.
你还要把整座炼狱打开吗
And you want to break down the entire dam?
是为了得到那些灵魂
To get the souls.
我就能阻止拉斐尔
I can stop Raphael.
拜托  你们必须相信我
Please, you have to trust me.
相信你
Trust you?!
你现在让我们怎么相信你
How in the hell are we supposed to trust you now?
我还是我
I'm still me.
我还是你们的朋友
I'm still your friend.
萨姆
Sam...
把你从地狱里救出来的是我
I'm the one who raised you from perdition.
什么
What?
恕我直言
Well, no offense...
你这活干得可不怎么利索
But you did a pretty piss-poor job of it.
等等
Wait.
你把我的灵魂落在地狱里
Did you bring me back soulless...
是有意的吗
on purpose?
你怎么会这样想
How could you think that?
小卡  我现在在想很多事情
Well, I'm thinking a lot of things right now, Cass.
听我说
Listen.
拉斐尔要把我们全部杀死
Raphael will kill us all.
他会将整个世界变成墓场
He'll turn the world into a graveyard.
我别无选择
I had no choice.
不  你有选择
No, you had a choice.
只是你选错了
You just made the wrong one.
你不明白
You don't understand.
事情很复杂
It's complicated.
其实不复杂  你自己也清楚
No, actually, it's not, and you know that.
不然你为什么瞒着不说
Why else would you keep this whole thing a secret, huh,
因为你心里明知道这是错的
unless you knew that it was wrong?
遇上这种烂事的时候
When crap like this comes around,
我们迎难而上
we deal with it...
就像我们一直做的那样
Like we always have.
唯一不可行的
What we don't do is we don't go out
就是去跟那魔鬼做交易
and make another deal with the devil!
你这样讲出来好像很简单
It sounds so simple when you say it like that.
可我需要听人忠告的时候你在哪里呢
Where were you when I needed to hear it?
我就在这里
I was there.
而你呢
Where were you?
你应该找我们帮忙的  小卡
You should've come to us for help, Cass.
也许吧
Maybe.
现在为时已晚
It's too late now.
我不能现在放弃
I can't turn back now.
我不能
I can't.
一点也不晚
It's not too late.
混蛋  小卡  我们能弥补这一切
Damn it, Cass! We can fix this!
迪恩  这没什么可补的
Dean, it's not broken!
快走
Run.
你们快走  走啊
You have to run now! Run!
哎哟
My, my.
又在玩火了
Playing with fire again?
如果你敢碰温氏兄弟
If you touch the winchesters...
我早听你说过了
Please. I heard you the first time.
我保证  他们狡猾的小脑袋上
I promise -- nary a hair on their
一根毛都不会少
artfully tousled heads.
再说了  我想他们印证了我的观点
Besides, I think they've proven my point for me.
到头来总是因为那些朋友  对吧
It's always your friends, isn't it, in the end?
我们尝试改变  尝试改进自身
We try to change. We try to improve ourselves.
但总有那么些个朋友抓着我们
It's always our friends who got to claw into our sides
阻止我们的前进
And hold us back.
你知道我看到了什么吗
But you know what I see here?
新一任上帝和魔鬼  进行合作
The new god and the new devil, working together.
够了
Enough.
别再说了
You stop talking.
从我眼前消失
And get out of my sight.
好吧
Well...
幸好我来了
Glad I came.
还有  不用客气
You're welcome, by the way.
知道咱们俩之间的区别吗
You know the difference between you and me?
我了解自己
I know what I am.
你又是什么  卡西迪奥
What are you, Castiel?
你究竟想做什么
What exactly are you willing to do?
你好  迪恩
Hello, Dean.
你怎么进来的
How'd you get in here?
鲍比在房子上画的那些天使防护阵
The angel-proofing Bobby put up on the house --
有几处画错了
He got a few things wrong.
真可惜我们居然还要防着你  对吧
Well, it's too bad we got to angel-proof in the first place, isn't it?
你来这里干什么
Why are you here?
我想跟你解释
I want you to understand.
相信我  我懂的
Oh, believe me, I get it.
为了打败拉斐尔神马的  对吧
Blah, blah, Raphael, right?
我这是为了你  迪恩
I'm doing this for you, Dean.
都是因为你我才这么做
I'm doing this because of you.
因为我
because of me. Yeah.
你逗我玩呢
You got to be kidding me.
是你让我了解了自由和自由意志
You're the one who taught me that freedom and free will --
你太幼稚了  知道吗
You're a freakin' child, you know that?
不是因为你无所不能
Just because you can do what you want
就可以无所不顾其极
Doesn't mean that you get to do whatever you want!
我知道我在干什么  迪恩
I know what I'm doing, Dean.
我不会跟你讲道理
I'm not gonna logic you, okay?
我要求你别那么做  没有为什么
I'm saying don't... Just 'cause.
我不想让你去做  仅此而已
I'm asking you not to. That's it.
我不明白
I don't understand.
除了萨姆
Look, next to Sam,
你和鲍比就是最像我亲人的家伙了
You and Bobby are the closest things I have to family --
你就像是我的兄弟
That you are like a brother to me.
所以  当我不想让你去做什么的时候
So, if I'm asking you not to do something...
你就应该听我的  兄弟
...You got to trust me, man.
否则呢
Or what?
否则我就要尽一切努力阻止你
Or I'll have to do what I have to do to stop you.
不可能的  迪恩
You can't, dean.
你只是个人类
You're just a man.
而我是天使
I'm an angel.
猜不准  可我也干掉过一些大人物
I don't know. I've taken some pretty big fish.
对不起  迪恩
I'm sorry, Dean.
那我也对不起了
Well, I'm sorry, too, then.
这就是一切原委
So, that's everything.
我想这就是你所谓的...
I believe it's what you would call a...
从人类角度来看  是场悲剧
Tragedy from the human perspective.
但也许人类的目光不那么深远
But maybe the human perspective is...Limited.
我不知道
I don't know.
所以我来问你了  父亲
That's why I'm asking you, father.
最后一次
One last time.
我做的对吗
Am I doing the right thing?
我选的道路对吗
Am I on the right path?
请你告诉我
You have to tell me.
请给我一个提示
You have to give me...A sign.
给我个提示
Give me a sign.
如果你不给的话
Because if you don't...
我只好
I'm gonna ju--
我只好去做
I'm gonna do whatever I...
我必须要做的事
Whatever I must.